MR. KOOL HAVIS

(470) 272-3790 • havisk@illinoisalumni.org

TECHNICAL PROJECT MANAGER/ ENGINEER/ CONSULTANT

Innovative and experienced technical project manager/consultant with a record of developing and supporting successful solutions incorporating a wide range of applications and technologies. Recognized and tasked by executive leadership to improve organizational effectiveness and efficiency through the proper implementation of development principles. Exemplary track record in leading teams in strategic project initiatives and guiding companies through consultive process implementation techniques. Innovative and forward-thinking leader utilizing progressive methods for team building and knowledge transfer in various industries. Diverse understanding of planning and directing various highly complex projects and effectively reducing company costs through innovative utilization of resources.

CORE COMPETENCIES

Problem Identification • Strategic and Tactical Planning • Budget Control • Contract Negotiation
Project Management • Relationship Management • Training • Data Analysis • Cost Reduction
Emergent Technologies • Design Review • Product Development • Technology Integration • Help Desk•
Hardware/Software Installation and Configuration • Advanced CRM Competency - Microsoft Dynamics CRM
Customization • UX/UI Design and Development • Web Application and Site Development

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: SQL, JavaScript, AngularJS, BackboneJS

JQuery, ReactJS, UnderScoreJS

Python, HTML5, CSS3, SASS, Git

Databases:Oracle, SQL Server and MS AccessOS Platforms:Mac, Microsoft Windows XP - 10, UNIXMethodologies:Agile, Waterfall, Iterative and Rational

Unified Process, Agile-Scrum

Others: SQL Analyzer, Microsoft Project 2010,

Sure Step, Unity3d, Blender

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

The Iron Yard

Front-End Engineer, Atlanta, GA

2015 to Present

A tweleve week immersive coding mentorship

- Build web apps and websites leveraging HTML5 and JavaScript (Plain, Angular, JQuery, React)
- Style using CSS3, SASS, Foundation
- Collaborate with others on projects
- Use Git for version control
- Work with RESTful web services
- Assure all user inputs are validated before submitting to back-end

American College Of Rheumatology, Atlanta, GA

MS Dynamics CRM Specialist

- Provide advice on CRM features and the use of the system.
- Subject matter expert during requirement qathering sessions
- Configure CRM to meet client's requirements
- Customize CRM as client's needs change.

2015 to 2015

MR. KOOL HAVIS PAGE 2

- Review JavaScript and remove code no longer needed
- Conduct root cause analysis for systems issues..
- Resolve CRM application errors and provide a solution to the issues in a cost-effective, efficient, and timely manner.

Affiliated Resource Group Inc., Dublin OH

MS Dynamics CRM Implementation Consultant

2013 to 2014

- Handled all aspects of client communication
- Utilized an automated issue tracking system to manage large complex projects
- Addressed prioritization and issue resolution
- Utilized a formal Change Management process to manage change approval and scope creep
- Assured project completion on time within budget
- Completed Business Requirement definition sessions with clients
- Converted Business Requirement into Functional requirements
- Tailored the Microsoft Dynamics System in a "shoulder to shoulder mode" with the client demonstrating the system capabilities
- Developed client specific training plans
- Developed training materials tailored to the client's CRM system configuration
- Built CRM Lab exercises that mirrored the training materials and reinforced knowledge
- Researched and provid training materials for CRM Team.

US Air National Guard, Marietta, GA **Cyber Transport Specialist**

2008 to 2014

- Provide mission critical voice, data, and video services, installing systems/circuits/IP-based, and managing infrastructure devices and systems using the latest approved software tools.
- Remove and replace assemblies and subassemblies to optimally sustain voice, data, and video networks, effectively managing projects and isolating malfunctions using diagnostic software, technical data, block diagrams, voltage and waveform measurements.
- Maintain network and circuit databases, records, and forms, coordinating requests for service orders, reviewing and recommending changes to communications-computer systems installations records (CSIR).
- Update and verify entries on system, facility, maintenance, and inspection records. Initiate, track, and maintain shipping, receiving, supply, and equipment documents.
- Conduct periodic inspections of systems installations and repair activities, interpreting
 inspection reports and implementing corrective actions, document inspection,
 and maintenance actions.
- Ensure equipment and components to meet installation practice technical order and are accepted for commercial installation specifications.
- Serve as advisor at meetings for facility design, military construction programs and minor construction planning, evaluating base comprehensive plan and civil engineering projects.

EDUCATION

Master of Information Technology, Project Management American InterContinental University Master of Science, Engineering Conservatory Tempe, AZ Bachelor of Science, Biochemistry University of Illinois Urbana-Champaign, IL

SECURITY CLEARANCE: Active